战争要来临了
There is a war coming.
可怕的战争
A-a terrible war.
到时会一片混乱
There-there will be chaos.
街上血流成河
Rivers of blood in the streets.
我知道的
I know it!
我能预见到
I-I can see it coming.
是时候了
It's time.
总得有人接替他  那不如就让我来
Somebody has to take over; it might as well be me.
我叫詹姆斯・戈登  我是一名警探
My name's James Gordon. I'm a detective.
我叫布鲁斯・韦恩
My name is Bruce Wayne.
我保证  我会找到凶手的
I promise, I will find the man who did this.
站住  不然我开枪了
Stop or I'll shoot!
马里奥・佩珀是被菲什・穆尼和警察陷害的
Mario Pepper was framed by Fish Mooney and the cops.
为什么要告你老板的密
Why snitch on your own boss?
你想篡菲什的位吧
You want to push Fish out, huh?
我告诉你了  这很重要
I told you this is important.
我要找的不是美女
I ain't looking for no girl.
而是武器
I'm looking for a weapon.
那老头必须死
The old man has to go.
他发现我们在合作
He figures we're working together,
我们就死定了
we'd be cooked.
你因涉嫌杀害
You're under arrest
奥斯瓦尔德・切斯特菲尔德・科波特被捕
for the murder of Oswald Chesterfield Cobblepot.
我去
Holy crap.
我是奥斯瓦尔德・科波特
I am Oswald Cobblepot.
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
本字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再加工制作
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
他还活着
He's alive?!
还活着
Alive?!
不可能
No!
老大  怎么了
Boss, what's wrong?
戈登没有照吩咐杀了企鹅
Gordon didn't kill Penguin like he was told.
什么
What?
企鹅还活着  而且还成了马罗尼的人
Penguin is still alive and working for Maroni?
不行
No.
找到戈登  带他来见我
You go find Gordon, and you bring him to me.
要活的
Still breathing.
我要跟这个小畜生好好谈谈
I want to talk to that son of a bitch.
你好  请留言
Hey, guys. Leave a message.
芭芭拉  你在家吗  听好了
Barbara, if you're at home, listen to me.
赶快离开那里
I need you to get out right now.
-我还以为我们是朋友  -哈维
- I thought we were friends. - Harvey!
给我闭嘴  都结束了
Shut up! Game's over.
如今我只能杀了你  带着你的尸首去见法尔科内
Now I got to kill you and take your body back to Falcone,
请求他  求他饶我一命
and beg, beg him for mercy!
听我说  我是搞砸了
Listen to me. I screwed up.
但我想好了挽回的办法
But I have a plan to make things right.
别杀我  帮我
Don't kill me. Help me.
你以为我是白痴吗
You think I'm an idiot?
走开
Walk away!
Walk away.
帮我吧
Help me.
我们不必这样两败俱伤
We don't have to go out like this.
你最好祈祷你再也不会见到我
You better hope you never see me again.
这地方好漂亮  是吧
What a place, huh?
美丽的家配美人儿
A beautiful home for a beautiful lady.
请告诉我你们想干什么
Please tell me what you want.
不妨跟你说实话好了
I guess there's no harm in the truth.
是这样  你男朋友本该为某人杀一个人
See, your boyfriend was supposed to kill a certain person for somebody.
但是呢  他没做到
Only, he didn't.
所以那个某人很生气
And now that somebody is real mad.
科波特
Cobblepot.
什么
What?
他没杀科波特
He didn't kill Cobblepot.
对了
There you go!
你消息还挺灵通
You're hip.
挺灵通
You are hip.
吉姆・戈登真是个幸运的小子
That Jim Gordon is one lucky son of a gun.
你这么瘦  才100磅吧
What are you, like, a hundred pounds?
110磅
110?
我打赌你这一头金发也是纯天然的
I bet that's your real hair color, too.
你们要对他...做什么
What are you gonna... do to Jim?
你跟罪犯交往过吗
You ever been with a criminal?
有些人觉得罪犯很性感
Some ladies find it a turn-on.
吉姆
Jim.
正说你呢
Speak of the devil.
我刚在跟你可爱的小女友增进了解呢
I was just getting to know your lovely lady.
你们这是非法闯入  滚出我家
You're trespassing. Get out.
别急啊  伙计
Slow down, hoss.
你搞错形势了  这里我说了算
You're misreading the situation. I'm the shot caller here.
现在的形势是  你老板要求你把我活着带回去
The situation is you've been told to bring me in alive,
否则我现在已经死了
or I'd be dead already.
但我很乐意这就把你们击毙
But I'm happy to kill you right here and now.
别这么横
Don't be such a hard-ass.
别这样  规矩你懂的
Come on, you know the rules.
只要你配合  乖乖受罚
You play nice, you take your lumps...
别人就不会受伤
nobody else gets hurt.
叫你伙计把枪放下  不然我一枪爆头
Tell your friend to drop his gun or I'll blow his brains out.
-老天  吉姆  -没事  我能处理
- Oh, my God, Jim. - It's okay. It's under control.
把枪放下
Drop your gun.
好吧
Okay.
按你的想法来
Have it your way.
但现在  等我们杀了你  金发妞就是下一个
But now, after we kill you, we're gonna kill blondie, too.
而且要慢慢来
Nice and slow.
我们得走了
We've got to go.
马上
Right now.
芭芭拉
Barbara.
西线州际特快五分钟后从12号站台出发
The Westbound Interstate Express departs in five minutes, Bay 12.
芭芭拉
Barbara.
-怎么  -听着
- What? - Listen.
不不  不行
No, no. No.
-就几天  我就来找你  -不要
- Just a couple of days and I'll join you. - No.
我还有事得处理
There are things I need to do.
好  你不走我也不走
Fine. Then if you stay, I stay.
好吗  我爱你  吉姆
Okay? Because I love you, Jim.
我不能离开你
I cannot leave you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
所以你必须离开
That's why you need to leave.
只要你安全了  他们就奈何不了我
If I know you're safe, there's nothing they can do to me.
事情解决了  我就来找你
I'll make things right, and then I'll come join you.
你要是没来呢
And what if you don't?
那就别回来
Don't come back.
再别回哥谭
Don't come back to Gotham.
不  吉姆
No, Jim.
翻译：灰灰是菇凉   艾瑞卡   木浅薰   Reginamoon   哥谭直属
翻译：Silence   DustD   charcie   爵士年代蓬蓬裙   夜影章鱼X
时间轴：Kallen   宝宝   讷讷       后期：饿得慌
特效：宝宝        校对&总监：草草
哥谭
第一季第七集
戈登来了
Gordon's here.
他疯了吗
Is he nuts?
他来干什么
What's he doing here?
难以置信
You believe this guy?
阿尔瓦雷斯
Hey, Alvarez.
你还有法官签的空头逮捕令吗
You got any of those blank warrants that Judge Bam Bam signed?
有啊
Uh... yeah.
这不可容忍
This cannot stand.
戈登必须死  布洛克必须死
Gordon must die, Bullock must die,
企鹅也必须死  就今天
Penguin must die today!
那马罗尼也得死咯
And Maroni, too, I suppose?
有必要的话
If need be.
你小题大做了  亲爱的
You're overreacting, my dear.
这个企鹅无足轻重
This Penguin's a nobody.
而你想为个给你打伞的家伙挑起战争
You want to start a war over the guy that carried your umbrella?
他就是我的跟屁虫
He was on my hip everywhere with me.
他知道些事情
He knows things.
什么事
Like what?
太多了
Too much.
他知道得太多了
He knows too much!
去找马罗尼
Go to Maroni
和气地问他愿不愿意把你的小跟班交出来
and ask him politely to hand over your little man.
和气点
Politely.
他要是不肯  我们就可以来硬的了
If he refuses, we can talk about stronger measures.
老大  这是示弱
Boss, this is weak response.
我真不想赞同菲什  但我们显示强硬态度
I hate to agree with Fish, but we need to show strength now.
我们得猛力回击  没得商量
We need to hit back hard. No talk.
干掉企鹅人  干掉戈登  结束
Penguin dead, Gordon dead, done.
镇定  尼克  我心里有数
Relax, Niko. I know what I'm doing.
戈登呢
Where is Gordon?
你不是说要带他一起来吗
I thought you were bringing him with you.
没有  他不肯乖乖就范
No. He wouldn't come without a struggle.
我不知道他逞强  还是根本就是疯了
Now, I don't know if he's playing tough or crazy,
但他居然跟没事人似的去上班了
but he's at work like nothing's wrong.
我会派维克多去找他
I'll send Victor to fetch him.
不需要  我的人能处理
No need. My guys can handle him.
我会派维克多去
I'll send Victor.
这真是只漂亮的鸡  不是吗
That's a nice handsome bird, huh?
我不了解鸡
I don't know chickens.
离远点
Fall back.
老家伙就在那边呢
The old man is right there.
去他的吧  他玩儿完了
Screw him. He's done.
我们该动手了
Now's the time to strike.
-还不到时候  -总是还不到时候
- Not yet. - Not yet, not yet.
现在不动手还要等什么时候  看看他
If not now, when? Look at him.
马罗尼家族都在笑话我们了  他却在玩儿鸡
Maroni clan are laughing at us, and he plays with chickens.
这正是我的忧虑之处
That's what has me worried.
他在玩儿鸡  他很高兴  放松
The chickens. He's happy, relaxed,
好像这世上没什么事让他操心
as if he doesn't have a care in the world.
-说明你那女孩活儿干得不错  -不
- That girl of yours is doing her job then. - No.
她说他都没碰过她一下
She says he hasn't even touched her.
她只是为他做饭  打扫卫生
She cooks and she cleans for him.
他喜欢看她做家务
He likes to watch her do chores.
好奇怪
Weird.
-但如果他就喜欢这个  -不对
- But if that's his thing... - No.
看他样子好像是知道了什么重要的事
He's acting as if he knows something important
别人却还蒙在鼓里
that no one else knows.
你来这儿干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
我在这儿工作  今天我当班
I work here. It's my shift.
不然我该去哪
Where else should I be?
阿拉斯加怎么样
How about Alaska?
逮捕令
Arrest warrants?
你要逮捕谁
For who?
奥布雷・詹姆斯市长  卡麦・法尔科内
Mayor Aubrey James, Carmine Falcone
还有他们的党羽
and their close associates.
罪名是在韦恩凶杀案中  共谋
On charges of conspiracy and perversion of justice
并妨碍司法公正
in the Wayne murder case.
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
没有
No.
也许有一点
Maybe a little.
但我感觉不错
Feels good.
反正他们也打算杀我
They're gonna try and kill me anyway.
我不如让他们也付出点代价
Might as well make them pay a price for it.
你要逮捕市长和法尔科内阁下  怎么做
You're gonna arrest the mayor and Don Falcone. How?
逮捕令上附着我的证词
My testimony is attached to the warrants.
光这一样就足以起诉他们一打罪名
That alone is enough to indict them on a dozen counts.
没错  如果你真能抓到人的话  但那不可能
Sure, if you could execute the warrants, which you can't.
如果地检官愿意起诉的话  但他不会愿意
If the D.A. Would prosecute, which he won't.
哥谭市不会有一个警察或者律师敢站出来帮你
There's not a single cop or lawyer in the city who will help you.
我认为只要反抗有成功的可能
I think there are plenty of people willing to help me
就会有很多人愿意帮我
once they see it's possible to fight back.
你这是在做白日梦  没人会帮你的
You're dreaming. Nobody will help you.
我是不会帮你的
I won't help you.
你以为我就不希望世道能有所改变吗
You don't think I want change just like you do?
我可是有家室的
I have a family.
我理解
I understand.
戈登...
Gordon...
离开这里吧
get out of town.
这是我的家
This is my home.
是我父亲的家
It was my father's home.
我是不会离开的
I'm not leaving.
大家好啊
Hello, everyone.
我叫维克多・萨斯
My name is Victor Zsasz.
我是由卡麦・法尔科内阁下亲自派来
I'm sent here personally by Don Carmine Falcone himself
处理一件他很在意的事  所以请放尊敬点
on a matter of deep concern to him, so please be respectful.
我来这里
I'm here
是为了找吉姆・戈登
for Jim Gordon.
只找他
Only him.
其他所有人  管好分内的事  我们就相安无事
Everybody else, mind your business and we're cool.
吉姆在哪里
So where's Jim at?
谢谢你们
Thank you.
吉姆
Hey, Jim!
Jim.
你好啊  吉姆
Hi, Jim.
放松
Relax.
我是来活捉你的
I'm supposed to take you in alive.
法尔科内阁下想和你谈谈
Don Falcone wants to talk.
告诉法尔科内我们会谈的
Tell Falcone we'll talk.
但不是今天
But not today.
别那样好吗
Don't be that way.
"活捉"的范围可广了
"Alive" is a very broad category.
一个人断了手  也是能活的
A man with no hands can still be alive.
这里有50个警察
There are 50 cops in here.
你试试啊
Try something.
所有人都出去
Everybody out.
拜托了
Please?!
走吧  头儿
Go, boss.
离开这里
Get out of here.
-吉姆...  -快走
- Jim... - Go.
我能应付
I can handle this.
现在怎么办  吉姆
Well, how now, Jim?
吉姆
Jim?
你为什么要躲着我呢  吉姆
Why are you hiding from me, Jim?
怎么回...
What the...?
那里
There!
要搭个便车吗
You need a ride?
快走  快快快
Go, go, go, go, go!
不要
No.
不要  求你了
No, please.
28个
Twenty-eight.
你醒了
You're back.
感觉如何
How do you feel?
糟透了
Terrible.
我在哪里  你是谁
Where am I? Who are you?
我是蒙托亚和艾伦的朋友
I'm a friend of Montoya and Allen.
我刚从你体内取出两颗子弹  并缝合了伤口
I just took two bullets out of you and sewed you up.
现在来看看你情况如何
Now I'm checking to see how you're doing.
那么
So...
你是谁  这是哪座城市
who are you, what city are we in,
今天是周几
and what day of the week is it?
我是詹姆斯・戈登
I'm James Gordon.
这里是哥谭
We're in Gotham.
今天是周五  怎么会有老鼠
It's Friday. Why are there rats?
这是大学的解剖实验室
It's the dissection lab at the university.
我听说你在躲避黑帮
I gather you're a fugitive from the mob.
不能去医院  克里斯帕斯说的
Can't go to the hospital, said Crispus.
还挺刺激的
Very exciting, I must say.
我昏迷了多久
How long have I been out?
大概几个小时  你很幸运
Just a couple of hours or so. You're very lucky.
重要器官都没...
No vital organs were...
别动  躺回去
Whoa, whoa, lie back down.
好吧  你受伤了
Okay? You are hurt.
得在床上躺一周...
Just a week or so in bed...
不行  我得走了
No, I have to go.
詹姆斯  你失血过多
James, you have lost a lot of blood.
你必须照我说的做  躺回去
You have to do as I say and lie back down.
不然你会死的
If you don't, you could die.
我得站起来  你能帮个忙吗
I have to stand. Can you help me?
好  好吧
Okay, okay.
克里斯帕斯
Crispus?
他说他要走了
He said he's leaving already.
-我必须马上走  -当然
- I have to go. Now. - Sure.
不过先穿上点衣服吧
Some clothes would be good though.
这关乎传统  价值观
This is about tradition, values.
告密者得受到惩罚  这是规矩
Snitches get stitches-- that's how it's always been.
你得把他交出来  萨尔
You need to hand him over, Sal.
我知道
I know.
这也应该
I should.
但没办法
But what can I say?
那小家伙会逗我开心
The little guy amuses me.
法尔科内阁下会很不高兴的
Don Falcone is going to be very unhappy.
你想为这个小瘪三而挑起战争吗
You want to start a war over this punk?
战争
War?
他对你们来说有那么重要吗
He's that important to you, is he?
不  他对我们而言什么都不是
No. He means nothing to us.
重要的是尊重
Respect is what matters here.
尊重  这我理解
Respect I understand.
企鹅
Penguin!
出来
Come on out here.
别怕  她又不会咬你
Don't be scared. She won't bite.
你不会咬他吧
You won't bite him, will you?
你好  企鹅
Hello, Penguin.
你好  穆尼女士
Hello, Ms. Mooney.
企鹅  穆尼女士和她的老大
Penguin, Ms. Mooney and her boss,
法尔科内先生  感觉你对他们有失尊重
Mr. Falcone, feel disrespected by you.
哎呀
Oh, dear.
那绝非我本意
Well, that certainly has never been my intention.
对他们而言  尊重十分重要
Well, respect is very important to them.
我要你为此
Now, I want a sincere apology from you
诚挚地道歉
for making them feel that way.
天哪  当然了
Oh, gosh, of course.
如果我有任何地方
If I've in any way
让任何人感到有失尊敬的话
caused anyone to feel a lack of respect,
我向你道歉
I apologize.
由衷地致歉
Sincerely.
他道歉了
There you go.
这下可以了吧
Can't say fairer than that.
既然这样  那就只能见血了
Bloodshed, then.
很好
I'm glad.
快乐的胖子太无聊了
Jolly fat men are so tiresome.
还有你
And you...
你这个
you little
卑鄙的小杂种
scaly-faced bitch.
我要怎么处置你呢
What I'm gonna do to you.
折磨简直是太便宜你了
"Torture" is far too nice of a word.
很抱歉你会这么想  菲什
I'm sorry you feel that way, Fish...
只有我的朋友  才能叫我菲什
Only my friends... call me Fish.
修女们
Hey, sisters!
你们好吗
How's it hanging?
马罗尼
运输存储公司
天呐
Holy...!
告诉你老大
Tell your boss
法尔科内是不会让马罗尼的卡车过桥的
Falcone won't let any of Maroni's trucks over the bridge.
除非他交出小企鹅
Not till he gives up Penguin.
听好了  你们得受点小伤
So, listen, you got to get hurt a little.
你们想挨揍还是挨子弹
You want a beating or a bullet?
我们为什么非要受伤
Why we got to get hurt?
因为我们要让你们老大知道问题的严重性
Because we're sending a message this is a serious issue.
我们会告诉他事态严重  放心吧
We'll tell him it's serious. No problem.
干脆这样吧
Ah, you know what?
他们怎么知道那辆运枪车的
How did they find out about the gun truck, huh?!
那辆车每周能赚300万啊
That's $3 mil per week right there!
王八蛋
Son of a bitch!
每周总收入450万  现金
$4.5 mil per, gross. Cash.
这一招很强硬啊
Very aggressive move, isn't it?
反应过激
An overreaction.
他们想吓住您
They want to scare you.
是嘛
Oh, is that right?
你认为他们觉得马罗尼阁下会害怕吗
You think that they think that Don Maroni can be scared?
你说得对  当然不会怕
Of course, you're right. No.
但是他们的反应为什么会这么激烈
But why, then, would they react so ferociously?
他们为什么就这么想抓我回去呢
Why do they want me back so badly?
我知道原因
I know why.
因为他们知道我这里有棵摇钱树
Because they know I got a stone moneymaker here.
会下金蛋的鹅
A golden goose.
他们知道  所以不想我们据为己有
They know it, and they don't want us to have him.
对吧  小企鹅
Right, Penguin?
呱呱
Honk, honk.
什么
What?
呱呱
Honk, honk.
鹅就是这么叫的
It's what geese say.
没错
Oh, right, right.
呱呱
Honk, honk.
好吧  他是只鹅
So, fine, he's a goose.
也许我们可以和他们谈判
Maybe we can negotiate a price,
-给他们些好处  -没错
- pay them off. - Yeah.
是啊
Yes.
谨慎是明智的
Caution is wise.
毕竟法尔科内家族的势力仍是最大的
The Falcone clan still is number one, after all.
给他们些好处比较保险
Paying them off is the safe thing to do.
去他的保险
Screw safe.
他们想逼我  让我知难而退
They want to push me? They think I'm gonna fold?
我会更狠地以牙还牙
I'll push right back, harder.
击中他们的软肋  今天就干
Hit them where it hurts. Today.
您心里有数
You know best.
如果您想这么搞
If that's how you want to play it,
我恰好知道软肋在哪里
I think I know just the spot to hit them.
我欠你一个道歉
I owe you an apology.
你说的是实话  但我不相信你
You were telling the truth, and I wouldn't believe you.
也许我对芭芭拉的个人情感
Maybe my personal feelings towards Barbara
影响了我的判断
got tangled up in there.
这是不对的
And that was wrong.
别在意了
Forget it.
不管怎样  很抱歉误会了你
Anyhow, I-I'm sorry for misjudging you,
我很高兴咱们是一边的
and I'm very glad that we're on the same side now.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
那么芭芭拉安全吗
So Barbara's safe though?
你确定她安全吗
You're sure she's safe?
我很确定
I'm sure.
戈登  是你吗
Gordon, is that you?!
没事的  阿尔弗雷德
It's all right, Alfred.
没事的  他是朋友
It's all right. He's a friend.
我们不能冒险直接接触
We couldn't risk a direct approach;
有很多人在找我
there's people looking for me.
好吧
Ah, right.
抱歉了  伙计
Sorry about that, mate.
小心驶得万年船
Can't be too careful.
有麻烦了  是吗  先生
In a spot of bother, are we, sir?
芮妮・蒙托亚和克里斯帕斯・艾伦
Renee Montoya and Crispus Allen.
很高兴见到你们
Pleased to meet you.
布鲁斯  我保证过找出杀害你父母的凶手
Bruce, I promised I would find your parents' killer.
我不确定我还能否兑现这个承诺
I'm not sure I'm going to be able to keep that promise.
说来话长  但我现在身处险境
It's a long story, but I'm kind of in a tight spot.
我惹恼了一些有势力的人
I've upset some powerful people.
别再把我当个孩子了
Stop treating me like a child.
解释清楚
Explain.
布鲁斯  你就是个孩子
Bruce, you are a child.
你不需要知道
You don't need to know...
你说你可能会死
You expect to die!
我想知道原因
I'd like to know why.
是和我父母被杀有关吗
Is it connected to my parents' murder?
是的  这里边千丝万缕
Yes, it's all connected.
纠结不清
Somehow.
布鲁斯
Bruce...
我会尽全力走出困境
I will do my best to work this thing out.
但如果我失败了
But if I don't,
蒙托亚和艾伦会接手你父母的案子
Montoya and Allen here will take over your parents' case.
我告诉了他们我所知道的一切
I've told them everything I know.
你可以百分百地信任他们
You can trust them, one hundred percent.
百分百
One hundred percent.
布鲁斯  他们是好警探
Bruce, these are good detectives.
如果有谁能找出真相  那就是他们了
If anyone can find the truth, it's them.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
先生  我们现在能帮上什么忙吗
Sir, what can we do to help you now?
帮不上了
Nothing.
从现在开始  我要独自面对
From here on in, I have to go it alone.
我不希望再有别人被扯进来
I don't want anyone else caught up in this.
我得走了
I have to go.
你路都走不稳
You can hardly walk.
我没事
I'll be fine.
好牌
Yeah.
归你了
All yours.
太厉害了
You are good.
闲杂人等
请勿入内
这边
This way.
不远了
Not much further.
就在那儿
It's there.
我都说过了嘛
Told you.
小菜一碟
Easy as pie.
这里应该有一百万的东西
There must be a million dollars' worth here.
嗯  你是说过
Yeah, you told us, all right.
你真聪明
You're clever.
太聪明了
You're very clever.
你这话好强的讽刺和敌意啊
I sense a sarcastic and hostile edge to your tone.
敌意
Hostile?
你还真说对了
You got that right.
你才不是什么金鹅  就是一告密小人
You ain't no golden goose, you're a yellow rat snitch,
你把马罗尼忽悠得晕头转向
and you got Maroni all twisted.
终于说清楚了  我好高兴
I'm so glad we're finally clearing the air at last.
没错  继续耍小聪明啊
That's it. Act smart, okay?
因为我现在只需要
'Cause all I got to do right now
往你脑门崩一枪
is put a bullet in your brain right here.
砰
Bang.
然后我回去跟老大说
See, then I go back and I tell the boss
尼克的人把你给毙了
that one of Niko's men shot you.
老天啊  真可惜
Gee, that's too bad.
你就玩完了
End of story.
是啊  这计划够聪明
Yes, that's clever enough.
我从不怀疑你的才智
I never doubted your intelligence.
这不是你的弱点
That's not your problem.
我还有弱点呢  我还有弱点
Oh, I got a problem, huh? I got a problem.
不  有麻烦的是你
No, you got a problem.
我有什么弱点  蠢货
What's my problem, schmo?
你的动力是什么
What drives you?
你的激情是什么
What's your passion?
只要知道一个人爱什么
When you know what a man loves,
就能置他于死地
you know what can kill him.
这人真疯得没边
Do you believe this guy?
对你来说  就是钱
For you, it's money.
你爱钱
You love money.
胜过权利和地位
More than power and respect.
你是个铁公鸡  卡彭先生
You're a skinflint, Mr. Carbone.
吝啬鬼
A cheapskate.
你们这是什么意思  放手
What are you guys playing at? Let me go!
对不住了  弗兰基
Sorry, Frankie.
-正如我所说的  吝啬鬼  -放手
- As I say, a cheapskate. - Hey, come on!
所以
Consequently,
你给手下的钱太少了
you don't pay your people enough.
住手  你们了解我的  不要惹祸上身
No, you know me. You don't want to do this.
-可悲的事实是...  -别这样
- It is a sad fact... - You don't want to do this.
-住手  住手  -贼是没有忠诚可言的
- No. No. No. No! - That there is no loyalty among thieves.
我只是提出多给他们点钱
The simple offer of a substantial pay raise
这两位就同意为我做事了
is all it took to sway these fine men.
知道了吧  这就是你的弱点
So, you see, that's your problem!
你的最爱成了你最大的软肋
Your greatest passion becomes your greatest weakness!
爱  卡彭先生
Love, Mr. Carbone.
爱能战胜一切
Love conquers all.
我的朋友
My friend.
亲爱的朋友  这是忧伤的一天
My good friend, today is a sad day.
尼克拉与我亲如父子
Nikolai was like a son to me,
弗兰基对你也是如此
just as Frankie was a son to you.
我们都失去了至亲的家人
We've both lost precious family members.
我向你表示哀悼
My condolences to you.
我也是
And mine to you.
我希望暴力事件能停止
I want this violence to stop.
现在情势很好
Business is good.
阿卡姆项目就是个金矿
The Arkham Project is a gold mine.
韦恩集团也继续合作了
Wayne Enterprises is back in play.
大家都好好的
Life is good for all of us.
何必赌上一切  为点小事而搅起战火呢
Why risk all of that and go to war over trifles?
那个小兄弟看来对你很重要
Your little man there is obviously very valuable to you.
你就留着他吧
We'll let you have him.
我们不会再动他了
Unharmed.
算是送你的礼物
Our gift to you.
不过礼尚往来  你也得表现出诚意
And as a show of mutual respect, you give us something in return.
比如呢
Like such as what?
地产如何
How about real estate?
不如就拿你们河边的一间仓库吧
One of your warehouses on the river maybe.
这可不行
That's not gonna work.
我喜欢这孩子
I mean, I like this fella,
但要用河边的仓库换的话...
but we're talking about a warehouse on the river.
好
Yeah.
印第安山
Indian Hill.
我可以把印第安山给你
I'll give you Indian Hill.
这地方我不太熟
I'm not familiar with the name.
在阿卡姆
It's in Arkham.
建在印第安坟场上的有毒废料填埋场
It's a toxic waste dump on top of an Indian burial ground.
毫无价值
It's worthless.
不
No.
任何东西都是有价值的
Nothing is worthless.
即使一分不值  也能有所用处
Even nothing is worth something.
我们要了
We'll take it.
算是我们相互尊重的象征  好吗
As a token of our mutual respect, yes?
当然  朋友
You got it, my friend.
多和气啊
It's all love.
很高兴见到你们
It's a pleasure seeing you all.
听说维克・萨斯大闹了哥谭警局
Um, I heard Vic Zsasz tore up the GCPD,
想找到戈登
tracking down Gordon.
抓到他了吗
Did you catch him yet?
还在办
We're working on it.
祝你们好运了
Well, good luck with that.
正直的人最危险了  对吧
There's nothing more dangerous than an honest man, huh?
小吉姆  是我  快开门
Jimbo, it's me. Open up.
别担心  我不是来杀你的
Don't worry, I'm not gonna kill you.
我应该杀了你的  但我不会的
I should, but I ain't.
那太好了
Glad to hear it.
显然  你选了他们肯定不会找的地方
Obviously, you figured you'd go to the last place they'd look,
因为这太明显  他们压根不会来这儿搜
because it'd be the first place they'd reject as being too obvious.
抱歉  我忘了介绍了
I-I'm sorry, I'm being rude.
这位是德文郡公爵夫人
This is the Duchess of Devonshire.
夫人  这是吉姆・戈登  是个白痴
Duchess, Jim Gordon, putz.
我是玛莎  你好啊
Marsha. Hi.
宝贝儿  你去逛逛吧
Baby, why don't you explore a little bit.
去卧室  换身凉快的衣服
Find the bedroom, put on your birthday suit.
我过会儿就去找你  好吗
And I'll find you in a jiffy, okay?
我考虑过了
So I've been thinking.
你还是个混蛋
You're still a douche bag.
但在理的是你
But you have the moral high ground.
所以我决定帮你一把  不管你想干什么
So I'm gonna back your play, whatever it is.
反正我横竖都是死
I figure I'm doomed anyhow.
倒不如跟好人搏一把
I might as well join the good guys.
多谢
Thank you.
你有什么计划
So what is your play?
你有计划吧  你说过你有的
I mean, you got one, right? You said you did.
明早我会逮捕法尔科内和市长
Tomorrow morning, I'm arresting Falcone and the mayor
指控他们陷害马里奥・佩珀
for the framing of Mario Pepper.
共谋  妨碍司法公正  腐败  全套
Conspiracy, POJ, Rico, the works.
你这...好个计划啊
Well, that's a... that's a hell of a plan.
你是不是跟一帮大猩猩
You sit down with a panel of chimpanzees
抽着可卡因想出来的
and a bucket of crack and come up with that one?
我琢磨不管结果如何  我们都会掀起波澜
I figure whatever else happens, we'll stir things up.
没准还能登报呢
We might even make the papers.
登报是肯定的
Oh, yeah, we're gonna make the papers, all right.
我们会横死街头
We're gonna be dead in the streets
正好能上晚报了
in time for the evening edition.
至少人民会知道真相
Well, at least the people will know the truth.
而我们会尽忠职守  为执法献身
And we'll go out doing our jobs, enforcing the law.
你就这么几句鼓励士气的屁话吗
That's the best inspirational speech you got?
尽忠职守
Doing our jobs?
你不用跟我一起来的
You don't have to join me.
不  我肯定加入
No, I'm game.
我说过  我横竖都是死
Like I said, I'm doomed anyhow.
现在  我要失陪一会儿了
Now, if you'll excuse me for one minute,
我还有点正事儿要办
just gonna take care of some business.
公爵夫人啊
Duchess!
马可
Marco!
波罗
Polo!
吓死我了
Jumping catfish.
早上好  詹姆斯市长
Good morning, Mayor James.
戈登  你吓着...
Gordon, you scared...
你吓死我了
scared the bejeebers out of me.
差点把咖啡都洒了
Almost spilled my coffee.
抱歉
Sorry.
市长  你被逮捕了
Sir, you're under arrest.
这可不好笑
That's not funny.
看听众是谁了
Depends where you're sitting.
你还是看看这个吧
Might want to take a look at this.
几位好啊
How you doing, guys?
我来见法尔科内先生
I'm here to have a chat with Mr. Falcone.
好的  市长先生
Sure thing, Mr. Mayor.
卡麦・法尔科内  你被捕了
Carmine Falcone, you're under arrest.
进去
Move.
都给我趴在那儿  别乱动
Lie down right over there. Stay quiet.
你这是想干什么
What on earth are you thinking?
我们想把你们俩一起送进监狱
We're thinking we'll take you both to jail
然后起诉你们共谋妨碍司法公正
and charge you with conspiracy to pervert the course of justice.
你要逮捕我  都别想活着走过街尾
Try and take me in, you won't make it to the end of the street.
我也是这么说的
That's exactly what I said.
这是合法逮捕  如果你拘捕  我们会开枪
This is a lawful arrest. If you resist, you will be shot.
这样啊
I see.
我们一起死个英勇壮烈
We all die together in a blaze of glory.
如果结局如此  我也不介意
If that's how it works out, that's fine with me.
你呢  哈维
How about you, Harvey?
不介意
Fine by me.
-老天啊  -我真羡慕你们
- Oh, God. - I envy you boys.
了无牵挂的感觉一定很轻松
Having nothing to lose must be liberating.
一定很不错
Must feel pretty good.
是啊
Yes, it does.
那如果你确实有什么牵挂呢
Suppose you did have something to lose.
你要怎么办
What would you do then?
比如
Suppose, for instance,
如果芭芭拉・基恩的脖子上现在正架着刀呢
I had a knife to Barbara Kean's throat right now.
你还会这么勇敢吗
Would you still be so brave?
这不是真的
You don't.
我告诉你是真的
I'm telling you I do.
你撒谎
You're a liar.
我有很多过失  但我不撒谎
I have many faults, but I'm not a liar.
芭芭拉在维克多・萨斯手上
Victor Zsasz has Barbara.
你认识维克多的
You know Victor.
你撒谎  她已经远走高飞了
You're lying. She's far away.
她回来了
She came back.
跑来我这儿为你求情
Came right to me to plead for your life.
你的女朋友真不错
You have a good woman there.
她非常爱你
She loves you very much.
太爱你了
Too much.
拿出证据
Prove it.
证明她在你手里
Prove you have her.
我当然可以
I could.
但我不会那么做
But I won't.
我要你相信我
I want you to believe me.
吉姆  他显然是在撒谎
It's obvious, Jim. He's lying.
是吗
Am I?
如果你是这么想
If you think so,
那就逮捕我吧
go ahead and try to bring me in.
你必死无疑
You'll be dead,
也就不会知道芭芭拉的命运会如何
so you won't know what happens to Barbara.
但肯定会很糟糕
But it won't be pretty.
撒谎
Lying.
以我母亲的坟墓起誓
On my mother's grave.
放下枪
Drop your gun,
芭芭拉就不会受到伤害
and Barbara won't be harmed in any way.
小松糕真香啊
Those muffins smell good.
不是给你的  变态
None for you, creep.
她如果想要  可以吃一个
She can have one if she wants.
不了  谢谢
No, thank you.
是
Got it.
可惜了
What a shame.
丢人丢到姥姥家了  他把你唬得投降了
Oh, this is embarrassing; he straight-up bluffed you into folding.
我们本可像英雄那样死去  这下要喂鱼了
We could've gone out like heroes; now we're fish food.
好吧  还真不是唬人
Okay, so it wasn't a bluff.
如果她受了点小伤  我很抱歉
I'm sorry if she was mistreated a little.
我们得确定她没有什么有用的信息
We needed to be sure she had nothing useful to tell us.
松绑  维克多
Untie her, Victor.
对不起
I'm sorry.
没事  没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
我要拿你怎么办啊
What am I gonna do with you?
按理说  你必须死
By rights, you have to die.
哎呦  我上班要迟到了
Whoa, hello. Uh, I'm late for work.
真是惊险刺激  我这就走了
Quite an adventure. I'll be on my way.
但真是可惜了
Such a waste though.
哥谭需要你这样的人  需要你们两个
Gotham needs men like you, both of you.
有原则的硬汉
Strong men with principles.
真希望我能让你明白  我不是你们的敌人
I wish I could make you see I'm not the enemy.
这个体制也不是敌人
The system is not the enemy.
混乱才是敌人
The enemy is anarchy.
但这我不是早就说过  吉姆
But I told you that before, didn't I, Jim?
是啊
Yes, you did.
但你却没听进去
You didn't listen though.
我们还有最后的晚餐  香烟什么的吗
Do we get a last meal or a smoke or anything,
还是就干耍嘴皮子
or just talk?
但今天  你相信了我
But today, you believed me.
你相信了我的话
You trusted my word.
这是很好的第一步
That's a good first step.
或许你还有希望
Perhaps there's still hope for you.
没错
Yes.
走吧  快走  趁我还没改主意
Go. Get out of here before I change my mind.
-等等  -闭嘴
- Wait a minute. - Quiet.
有幸认识你  芭芭拉
It's been a pleasure, Barbara.
我欣赏勇敢的女人
I do admire a brave woman.
你打的什么主意
What's the catch?
吉姆  他说可以走了  别磨叽了
Jim, he said we could go. Let's not haggle here.
你打的什么主意  法尔科内先生
What's the catch, Mr. Falcone?
我要你好好想想我的话
I want you to think about what I said.
我希望你能理解真理
I want you to understand the truth.
别无所求
That's all I ask.
我打的主意是
The catch is...
很快  你就会明白我是对的
someday soon, you'll see I'm right.
芭芭拉
Barbara...
对不起
I'm sorry.
我是想帮忙
I was just trying to help, and...
我不知道我...
I don't know what...
我好爱你
I love you so much.
太棒了
Excellent.
真好吃
Delicious!
好啊
Yes.
我严格按照食谱做的
I followed the recipe.
你说得对  法先生  烹饪很简单
You're right, Mr. F., cooking is easy.
抱歉之前让你目睹那种事
I'm sorry you had to see all that earlier.
太不好了
Not pleasant.
我理解的
I understand.
生意就是生意嘛
Business is business.
是啊
Yes, it is.
我去看看鸡
I'll go see to the chickens.
下蛋了吗  亲爱的
Any eggs, my dears?
法尔科内阁下
Don Falcone.
我的朋友
My friend.
见到你真好
Good to see you.
我正在想我们遇见的那天晚上呢
I was just thinking about the night we met.
放他们下来
Cut them down.
那个告密的呢
Where's the snitch?
我要跟他说话
I want to speak to him.
科波特  是吧
Cobblepot, is it?
人之将死其言也善
Condemned men are honest men, I find.
你死前有什么能跟我说的
What can you tell me before you go?
法尔科内阁下
Don Falcone.
真是太荣幸了  先生
It is a great honor, sir.
我可以告诉您一个很有价值的秘密
Indeed, I can tell a secret of great value to you...
只要您答应我最后一个要求
if you grant me one last request.
什么要求
Which is what?
把杀我的任务交给詹姆斯・戈登
Give the job of killing me to James Gordon.
为什么
Why him?
他是受您摆布的人中  唯一有良心的
He's the only man under your sway who has a conscience.
他是唯一可能饶我一命的人
The only one who might be persuaded to spare my life.
我凭什么要答应你
Why would I agree to that?
我想要你死  你是个告密鬼
I want you dead. You're a snitch.
如果您同意  而戈登又饶了我一命
If you agree and Gordon spares me,
那我就做您的眼线
then I will become your snitch.
永远
For life.
我会换个名字回到哥谭
I will come back to Gotham under a different name,
我会想办法打入马罗尼家族
and I will work my way into the Maroni family,
我会为您提供消息
and I will snitch for you.
我非常擅长做这种事
I am excellent at this sort of work.
我有这方面的天赋  真的  先生
I have a gift for it. I really do, sir.
好
Deal.
我会让戈登去杀你
Gordon will get the job of killing you.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
那个有价值的秘密是什么
What is the valuable secret?
对了
Oh, yes.
菲什・穆尼和俄国人尼古拉只是假装不睦
Fish Mooney and Nikolai the Russian only pretend to hate each other.
他们是情人
They're lovers.
菲什在鼓动尼古拉夺您的权
And Fish is pushing Nikolai to take your place.
是嘛
Is that so?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
但菲什只是为了再夺他的权
But only so Fish can take over from him.
真是个好秘密
That is a good secret.
简直难以置信
It's almost uncanny.
一切正如你所说的那样
Everything played out exactly as you said it would.
我们轻松除掉了尼古拉
We got rid of Nikolai painlessly,
马罗尼则把你当宝贝
and Maroni thinks you're a wizard.
你的确很有天赋
You really do have a gift.
但我觉得放走戈登是个错误
But I think we're making a mistake letting Gordon live.
他会惹麻烦
He's trouble.
多谢您饶他一命
Thank you so much for sparing him.
多谢您给这个面子
I appreciate the favor.
别担心
Don't worry.
他会明白过来的
He'll see the light.
无论如何  我保证
One way or another. I guarantee it.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com